<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outbreaker2 on RECON learn</title>
    <link>https://reconlearn.netlify.com/tags/outbreaker2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outbreaker2 on RECON learn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2017 Thibaut Jombart</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reconlearn.netlify.com/tags/outbreaker2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola simulation part 2: outbreak reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://reconlearn.netlify.com/post/practical-ebola-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reconlearn.netlify.com/post/practical-ebola-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>This practical is the second part of the response to a simulated Ebola Virus Disease (EVD) outbreak taking place in the city of Ankh, Republic of Morporkia. While the first part focussed on early assessments of transmissibility, this part explores more methodological options for estimating transmissibility, and provides an introduction to outbreak reconstruction using outbreaker2.

An update on the EVD outbreak in Ankh, Republic of Morporkia After some rather concerning preliminary results on the new EVD outbreak in the city of Ankh, Republic of Morporkia, Public Health Morporkia (PHM) has sent you updates of the linelists and contact data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outbreak investigation using outbreaker2</title>
      <link>https://reconlearn.netlify.com/post/lectureoutbreaker2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reconlearn.netlify.com/post/lectureoutbreaker2/</guid>
      <description>This short lecture gives a primer on some methodological aspects of outbreak reconstruction using outbreaker2.
Slides Click on the image below to access the slides:
    About this document Contributors  Thibaut Jombart: initial version
 Finlay Campbell: figure on outbreaker2’s contact model
  Contributions are welcome via pull requests. The source file can be found here.
 Legal stuff License: CC-BY Copyright: Thibaut Jombart, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>