<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ebola on </title>
    <link>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/topics/ebola.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ebola on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/topics/ebola/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola simulation part 1: early outbreak assessment</title>
      <link>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/simulated-evd-early.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/simulated-evd-early.html</guid>
      <description>This practical simulates the early assessment and reconstruction of an Ebola Virus Disease (EVD) outbreak. It introduces various aspects of analysis of the early stage of an outbreak, including contact tracing data, epicurves, growth rate estimation from log-linear models, and more refined estimates of transmissibility. A follow-up practical will provide an introduction to transmission chain reconstruction using outbreaker2.

A novel EVD outbreak in Ankh, Republic of Morporkia A new EVD outbreak has been notified in the small city of Ankh, located in the Northern, rural district of the Republic of Morporkia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola: building few models for Ebola</title>
      <link>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/practical-compartmental-ebola.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/practical-compartmental-ebola.html</guid>
      <description>This practical aims to illustrate the basics of Ebola modelling using R, with an emphasis on how the method works.
We will start with a basic model for Ebola. We will then illustrate how to account for an evolving context, e.g. implementation of control measures. Finally, we will explore basic principle of model fitting.
Core Concepts From the previous lecture, we will further develop these concepts:
 Compartmental models Flow diagrams and writing down a model Natural history of Ebola Control strategies Introduction to model fitting  Required packages install.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>