<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zulma Cucunuba on </title>
    <link>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/authors/zulma-cucunuba.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zulma Cucunuba on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/authors/zulma-cucunuba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Concepts on Vector Borne Disease Modelling</title>
      <link>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/basicvbdmodelling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/basicvbdmodelling.html</guid>
      <description>This lecture is about Vector Borne Diseases (VBD) modelling. The aim is to gain a general understanding on the role of modelling on the main vector borne diseases, with special enphasis on Malaria, Chagas and Zika.
Slides Click on the image below to access the slides:
  
About this document Contributors  Zulma Cucunuba &amp;amp; Pierre Nouvellet: initial version  Contributions are welcome via pull requests.
Legal stuff License: CC-BY Copyright: Zulma Cucunuba &amp;amp; Pierre Nouvellet, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola: building few models for Ebola</title>
      <link>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/practical-compartmental-ebola.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/practical-compartmental-ebola.html</guid>
      <description>This practical aims to illustrate the basics of Ebola modelling using R, with an emphasis on how the method works.
We will start with a basic model for Ebola. We will then illustrate how to account for an evolving context, e.g. implementation of control measures. Finally, we will explore basic principle of model fitting.
Core Concepts From the previous lecture, we will further develop these concepts:
 Compartmental models Flow diagrams and writing down a model Natural history of Ebola Control strategies Introduction to model fitting  Required packages install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VBD: building a simple model for Zika</title>
      <link>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/practical-vbd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reconlearn-ld.netlify.com/post/practical-vbd.html</guid>
      <description>This practical aims to illustrate the basics of vector borne disease (VBD) modelling using R, with an emphasis on how the methods work. We will use a basic model for an arboviral infection as an example. In this practical we will begin by gaining some understanding of the components which contribute to R0 and how potential interventions influence transmission. Later in the practical you will construct a model of Zika transmission to look at the effects of several parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>